ADAM GIRARD-MCFADDEN

adam_m_20@hotmail.com | C:613-262-6482 | Nepean ON, K2J 6L6

LinkedIn: https://tinyurl.com/rew3yn | Github: https://github.com/adamgmcfadden

Portfolio: https://tinyurl.com/3bzdaray

A highly motivated and fully bilingual professional entering a second career in Web Development and looking for an opportunity in the Ottawa tech market. Ready for any junior developer role with a diploma from the Coding (Full-Stack Web Development) Bootcamp at Carleton University, newly developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, the MERN Stack and an abundance of soft and hard skills polished from a decade long engineering career

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, React.js, Bootstrap, AJAX

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Node, Handlebars, Webpack, GraphQL, C#/.Net, Python

PROJECTS

LETTUCE-PLAN-THIS-THYME | Repo: https://tinyurl.com/4uuvcmbh | Deployed: https://tinyurl.com/cfbuup8x

- What it does: Meal Planning Application.
- What it accomplishes: Once signed in, a user can search for recipes fetched from a server-side API with keywords and save these recipes to their favourites and/or to a calendar to manage their meal schedule.
- My responsibility: Project Management, establishing the Model/View/Controller (MVC) structure, creation and maintenance of the GitHub repository, creating the Models and their associations, and front-end design.
- Languages: CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars.
- Tools: Express.js, Express-Session, Express-Handlebars, Bootstrap, Sequelize.js, Connect-Session-Sequelize, MySQL2, dotenv, bcrypt, Nodemailer.

CAT WORX - C# - EMPLOYEE BADGE MAKER | Repo: https://tinyurl.com/bdzxxzwd

• What it does: A back-end only C# application that uses .Net framework to generate Employee Badges either manually, or by utilizing a Random User Generator API. Idea provided by Carleton University.

NEWSFEED - PYTHON | Repo: https://tinyurl.com/nyv6dyyp | Deployed: https://tinyurl.com/nyv6dyyp

• What it does: An application that allows its users to share Tech related news with other users, comment on posts, and upvote comments (refactored from original "just-tech-news" repo to rebuild the app with Python and Flask framework for the front end and template engine, instead of Node.js and Handlebars. SQLAlchemy was used to interact with the MySQL database.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hurley Ventilation Technologies Inc.

Sudbury, ON

Project Manager + Technical Design/Drafting

May 2019 to Sept 2020

- Analyzed RFPs/RFQs and formulated scopes, schedules, and budgets for main mine ventilation projects
- Led project team to ensure project successful completion on time and on budget
- Completed quality control testing
- Commissioned main mine ventilation systems
- Ventilation design for main and auxiliary systems
- Drafting of general arrangement and construction drawings for bidding and fabrication

Cambrian College of Applied Arts and Technology

Sudbury, ON

Professor of Mine Ventilation Planning (Part-Time)

Sept 2019 to Dec 2019

- Created and taught a lesson plan for the 3rd year Mine Ventilation Planning Course of Mining Engineering Technology program.
- Curriculum included auxiliary and main ventilation design, responsibilities of a ventilation technician/engineer, ventilation modelling with VUMA, ventilation spreadsheet creation.
- Created and graded labs, projects, quizzes, tests, and exams to evaluate student understanding and progression.

Alamos Gold Inc. (Previously Richmont-Mines Inc.)

Dubreuilville, ON

Ventilation Specialist

Feb 2015 to May 2019

- Produced ventilation department yearly and quarterly forecast & budget
- Mentored and trained ventilation technicians
- Produced Life of Mine (LOM) ventilation plan
- Oversaw all ventilation projects and ensured their successful completion
- Produced short and mid-term ventilation designs to meet production and development goals

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development (6 Month Bootcamp)

Carleton University

Mining Engineering Technology Diploma (3 Year Program)

Cambrian College of Applied Arts and Technology

Mining Engineering Technician Diploma (2 Year Program)

Cambrian College of Applied Arts and Technology